<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dingoo on Dave&#39;s Hacks</title>
    <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/tags/dingoo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dingoo on Dave&#39;s Hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2019 David Roberts</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidatroberts.github.io/tags/dingoo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenDingux 3D (slow edition)</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/2015-07-29-dingux3d_temp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/2015-07-29-dingux3d_temp/</guid>
      <description>Looking back on these posts, I should probably try to update them a little more frequently. I think I might stick to relatively short posts, that way I might actually get some more out!
Anyway, in the last post I described how I set up a development environment that was basically Xubuntu running in a virtual machine, and then SSHing into that from OS X. Well I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting that to use building a simple little software renderer for the Dingoo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenDingux Dev Environment for OS X (sort of)</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/2014-10-11-opendingux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/2014-10-11-opendingux/</guid>
      <description>A couple of years ago I picked up a Dingoo A320, it was awesome especially for commuting back and forth to Sky where I was working at the time. Anyway things change and inevitably it ended up in the back of a draw. Having moved house again, I found it, though there were a few scratches on the screen that were quickly taken care with good ol&amp;rsquo;Brasso. I decided that it was time for me to make something for it and learn SDL during the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nLove, Dingoo and fonts</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/nlove-dingoo-and-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/nlove-dingoo-and-fonts/</guid>
      <description>For anyone who&amp;rsquo;s been following my twitter feed you may know that I&amp;rsquo;ve been starting to develop a game in Lua and LOVE, a 2D game engine. After messing about with LOVE I found out that there was a version of love2D for the dingoo, canoo and gp2x called nLove. This is a great library that allows me to develop a game on my mac, using LOVE and then run it on my dingoo using nLove.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>