<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chumby on Dave&#39;s Hacks</title>
    <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/tags/chumby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chumby on Dave&#39;s Hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2019 David Roberts</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidatroberts.github.io/tags/chumby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning a Chumby with Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/2019-05-08-cleaning-chumby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/2019-05-08-cleaning-chumby/</guid>
      <description>I never really get rid of many of my tech gadgets, which is why I still have my old iBook in a draw somewhere, a Pokemon Mini in a box in the loft as well as a couple of Cybikos hanging around. This of course means I&amp;rsquo;ve still got my Chumby One that following tradition has been stuck in a drawer since I moved to Newcastle about 3 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chumby and Go</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/2013-11-17-chumby-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/2013-11-17-chumby-go/</guid>
      <description>A number of years ago I purchased a Chumby One, basically a fancy alarm clock running linux. I&amp;rsquo;ve played with a few different languages for it but haven&amp;rsquo;t really done much with it lately. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been using a bit of Go recently and thought it might be fun to get Go running on the Chumby One, this has actually proven to be remarkably easy thanks to Go already coming with a number of compilers for different architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chumby, lua and segmentation fault</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/chumby-lua-and-segmentation-fault/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/chumby-lua-and-segmentation-fault/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been digging through some of my older projects (read abandoned) and I came across a small lua library I had started writing to interface with the frame buffer on the Chumby, source available:
 If I remember correctly the library works and allows you to draw to the screen using lua however it produces a segmentation fault I tracked the error down to the setup method that gets called when the library is first loaded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chumby - FTP</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/chumby-ftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 20:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/chumby-ftp/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning on turning the Chumby into a websever using lighttpd, thought it&amp;rsquo;d be kind of cool to make it do something useful rather than just standing there and showing me the time or recent facebook updates. My first idea was to just put my site on a usb disk, then run lighttpd. This was all well and good, but everytime I updated the site I had to unplug the usb disk, update the files, re-insert and then restart the chumby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chumby - C/C&#43;&#43; Framebuffer</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/43870836/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 21:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/43870836/</guid>
      <description>Last year sometime I purchased a chumby one, with the main goal to develop some funky widgets and also I needed a new alarm clock. The widgets that are on the chumby site are all developed in flash, and I never quite got round to paying the massive price for the flash SDK, but luckily on the good ol&amp;rsquo;chumby board they&amp;rsquo;d released a C/C++ compiler. All great - except that there was no Mac OSX toolchain and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like trying to get it to compile on OSX, lucky for me a native C++ compiler was made available.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>