<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Dave&#39;s Hacks</title>
    <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Dave&#39;s Hacks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2019 David Roberts</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 19:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidatroberts.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meggy Jr, weather and temperature</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/meggy-jr-weather-and-temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/meggy-jr-weather-and-temperature/</guid>
      <description>For my birthday my girlfriend got me a Meggy Jr! it&amp;rsquo;s an awesome build-it-yourself handheld based on the arduino platform with an 8by8 pixel RGB screen. I initially thought about creating a sort of Pacman clone, I got so far and then got bored of just copying a game that&amp;rsquo;s been done half a hundred times.
So&amp;hellip;instead I decided to have the Meggy Jr alternately display the temperature and an icon representing the weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gameduino: Sprite Tutorial 1</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/gameduino-sprite-tutorial-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 18:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/gameduino-sprite-tutorial-1/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago on KickStarter I sponsored a project called the Gameduino, an add on shield for the Arduino, advertised as a game adapter for the Arduino. This is an awesome little device that has 32Kb of RAM, brings support for VGA output, stereo sound and has a co-processor that runs forth. See the official site for more information: http://excamera.com/sphinx/gameduino/. About two weeks ago mine arrived and since then in some of my spare time I&amp;rsquo;ve been working out how to output sprites and generally figuring out how it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino and PySerial</title>
      <link>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/arduino-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidatroberts.github.io/post/arduino-and-python/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier post I mentioned briefly about using pySerial to send data to and from the arduino using Python, in this post I&amp;rsquo;ll go through a bit more about how to set this up.
First you&amp;rsquo;ll need pySerial, which can be downloaded from here. For windows users there is an installer package. For other OSs, download the source from the same link and in a terminal enter the pyserial-x.y directory and then for python3 users enter _python3 setup.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>